globalshiksha.com 2011-06-29

# Privacy policies of globalshiksha.com

**Introduction**

globalshiksha.com is an internet and mobile service that allows users to create personal web profiles and communicate and share content with friends and other users. To help our members identify and interact with each other, we request and display some personal information to other members and visitors. globalshiksha.com members can change their profile information at any time and can control how other members and the service communicates with them.

globalshiksha.com cares deeply about online privacy. If you have any questions concerning this privacy policy, please email us at [privacy@globalshiksha.com](mailto:privacy@globalshiksha.com).

 **Process of Information Collection and Use by globalshiksha.com**

globalshiksha.com collects user submitted information such as name, email address, and age to authenticate users and to send notifications to those users relating to the globalshiksha.com service. globalshiksha.com also collects other profile data including but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, education and occupation in order to assist users in connecting with each other. Further, in order to facilitate commerce, we collect credit card information, member's address, or bank information only from those who choose to join globalshiksha.com.

globalshiksha.com also logs non-personally-identifiable information including IP address, profile information, aggregate user data, and browser type, from users and visitors to the site This data is used to manage the website, track usage and improve the website services. This non-personally-identifiable information may be shared with third-parties to provide more relevant services and advertisements to members. User IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

User Profile information including members' pictures and user names are displayed to people in order to facilitate user interaction in the globalshiksha.com social networking community. Email addresses are used for the purposes of inviting new friends to join globalshiksha.com, to add users to members' friends' networks, and to send notifications related to the service. With the exception of inviting friends, adding friends, and notifications, a user's email address is not shared or displayed to people within a user's personal network. Users within a personal network communicate on globalshiksha.com with each other through the globalshiksha.com service, without disclosing their email addresses. Users' full names are never directly revealed to other members. To facilitate searching and finding friends and acquaintances on the service, globalshiksha.com allows users to search for other members using first and last name, email address, interests and schools where users may have attended.

We may also use a user's email address to send updates, a newsletter or news regarding the service. Users may choose not to receive email of this type by changing their "notification" setting to "Do not send me notification emails" in the user "Account Settings".

From time to time, globalshiksha.com or a partner may advertise on globalshiksha.com. Users may be asked to provide personal information including name, email address or home address in order to participate or receive a response from globalshiksha.com or one of its partners. We may transfer personal information to certain ad partners that you have explicitly requested to receive information from or expressed an interest in.

 **Use of Cookies**

globalshiksha.com uses cookies to store visitors' preferences and to record session information, for purposes including ensuring that visitors are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize newsletter, advertising, and Web page content based on browser type and user profile information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set -- each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences -- however, you must enable cookies from globalshiksha.com in order to use most functions on the site Please note that globalshiksha.com allows 3rd party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the globalshiksha.com Privacy Policy.

 **Invitations and Communication to Non-members**

globalshiksha.com members can invite friends to join the service by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. globalshiksha.com stores the email addresses that members provide so that the respondents may be added to the friend's list of the member sending the invitations, and also to send reminders of the invitations. globalshiksha.com does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations. Recipients of invitations from globalshiksha.com may contact globalshiksha.com to request the removal of their information from our database.

 **Links**

globalshiksha.com contains links to sites. globalshiksha.com is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on globalshiksha.com

 **Blogs, Bulletin Boards, Buzz and Public Forums**

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to blogs, bulletin boards, Buzz or any other Public Forums that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

 **Email Choice**

Members who no longer wish to receive updates or notifications may choose not to by selecting the appropriate options in the user profile 'Account Settings'. All notification emails and globalshiksha.com newsletters also include the above instructions for opting-out of those communications in the future.

 **Advertising**

Ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to users by globalshiksha.com or one of our Web advertising partners. Our Web advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by globalshiksha.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

 **Security**

globalshiksha.com member accounts are secured by member-created passwords globalshiksha.com takes precautions to insure that member account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time For any additional information about the security measures we use on globalshiksha.com, please email us at info@globalshiksha.com

 **Sharing and Disclosure of Information globalshiksha.com Collects**

Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, globalshiksha.com will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by globalshiksha.com, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the globalshiksha.com Terms of Use Agreement or to protect our rights; or (3) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service. globalshiksha.com reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of globalshiksha.com or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest For more information see the "Changes in Our Privacy Policy" section below.

 **Changes in Privacy Policy**

From time to time we may make changes to our privacy policy If we make changes, we will post them on our site to make users aware of what the changes are so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. A User is bound by any minor changes to the policy when she or he uses the site after those changes have been posted If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days.

 **Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us at: [info@globalshiksha.com](mailto:info@globalshiksha.com)
